Hello, Handler One.
May 22nd, Stellar Year 2148
This is Spearhead Squadron's
combat commander,
Personal Name: Undertaker.
We've received word of a new Handler coming.
We look forward to working with you.
As do I.
Nice to meet you, Undertaker.
May 22nd, Stellar Year 2148
Hey, there.
Hey.
The new one seems pretty dangerous.
The new Handler! Did you forget already?
Shin! Shinei Nouzen!
You did it again, you bastard!
Old man Aldrecht's about to go off again.
You need something?
Don't give me that!
I need to know why you keep smashing up
your machines on every mission!
I keep telling you they have
weak legs! So don't push them!
Sorry.
We don't have any more spare parts!
We won't be able to repair it
until the next batch of them comes!
Fido should've brought back Kujo's machine.
Yeah, I guess we can use
the ones from theirs.
But are you okay with using parts
from a machine someone died in?
I guess it's a little late to ask that.
Got it, Undertaker.
Kujo was lucky to die in a unit
that had you.
You take the other Processors, too.
By the way, I heard the news.
What's the new Handler like?
Fine.
"Fine"? Listen, you...
They synch'd to say "hello,"
that they want to maintain good lines
of communication, and will be calling every day.
Rare, for a Republic soldier.
So, what you'd call an "ordinary person"?
They must live a hard life, the poor thing.
May 29th, Stellar Year 2148
Ready... Go!
Got it!
Yes!
There!
Big haul, huh?
We'll have a party tonight!
You good to go, Fido?
This isn't bullying, okay?
No telling Shin.
Is that a "yes"? Or a "no"?
You guys who are out on a walk,
can you hear me?
What's up, Theo?
Weather report's changed.
Rain's coming.
Eintagsfliege.
Jammers, too.
That means the radar will be down.
When will they get here?
In about two hours, I'm told.
Got it. Heading back.
No Shepherds this time, it seems.
They'll just try and overwhelm you.
Just Sheep?
A duck hunt, then.
Good, everybody's here.
Attention.
I'll explain the situation.
There's one swarm close by,
and another linking up with it from the rear.
Supplying the first, probably.
As soon as that's done, they'll attack.
We'll ambush them
at point 304 on their route.
Establish a kill zone on Main Street,
where we'll eliminate most of the enemy.
Even in spring, it gets cold
when the sun disappears.
The cockpit gets awful cold,
considering how cramped it is.
Well, the armor's paper-thin
and has plenty of gaps in it.
And it's slow.
And it breaks easily.
Yup. It's a piece of shit.
Handler One to all units.
The enemy appears to be approaching.
Deploy to Point 208 and intercept them!
Undertaker to Handler One.
We're already deployed.
We'll intercept them
at point 304, farther ahead.
That's fast.
You're as good as they say, Undertaker.
Here they come.
The Legion's out in force again today.
Scout type Ameise
Well, they're mostly Ameise.
They're easy to destroy, but obnoxious.
Dragoon type Grauwolf
Grauwolfs? What a pain.
I guess we have to take this seriously.
I really hate that guy.
Tank type Löwe
A Löwe's main gun is twice
as powerful ours.
It can kill you fast.
Electronic-Disruption type Eintagsfliege
Okay, time to get to work.
Open fire.
Third platoon, withdraw to the southeast,
and keep your current targets close to you.
Fifth platoon,
maintain your current position.
When an enemy platoon enters the kill zone,
wipe them out with coordinated fire.
Black Dog, roger.
Snow Witch, reload while you can.
Snow Witch, roger.
As always, thanks for the reminder.
Laughing Fox, same.
Don't shoot me, Black Dog!
All units, cease fire! Split up!
Handler One to all units!
That's Long-Range-Gunner type
Skorpion fire. Be careful.
I'm sending you the estimated location
of their spotters.
Three potential locations.
Confirm and take them out.
Gunslinger, four units at a distance of 1200,
heading 0-3-0, on the roof.
Roger. On it.
Handler One, directional laser-based data
transmissions can reveal our location.
Please limit yourself to verbal
communication during operations.
I'm sorry.
The next set of observers
will be appearing soon.
Keep me informed of their location.
Understood!
There's an awful lot
of them today, Undertaker.
Duck hunt, right?
Just enjoy yourself.
There are definitely more Löwes
than expected.
The restricted vision makes them
more dangerous, too.
We should start whittling down their numbers.
You make it sound easy.
I'll handle the Löwes. You deal with
the others and take command.
Roger that. Don't make Aldrecht
scream his head off again!
Undertaker, what are you doing?
So this is... Undertaker?
Handler One to all units!
That's Long-Range-Gunner type
Skorpion fire. Be careful.
May 29th, Stellar Year 2148
I'm sending you the estimated location
of their spotters.
Three potential locations.
Confirm and take them out.
Handler One, directional laser-based data
transmissions can reveal our location.
Please limit yourself to verbal
communication during operations.
I'm sorry.
The next set of observers
will be appearing soon.
Keep me informed of their location.
Understood!
Stellar Year 2139, nine years ago...
War was declared on the Republic of
San Magnolia by the neighboring Empire of Giad.
They began an invasion with their
autonomous combat machines, the Legion.
But we estimate that, in fact,
Giad had been wiped out by its own
out-of-control Legion four years prior.
Given that all Legion have an operating time
of 50,000 hours—approximately six years—
they will completely shut down
in about two years.
Thus, you new soldiers will have only
two years before the war ends.
But during that time, we hope
you'll do your best to fulfill your duties.
After all, the Republic's Juggernauts
are vastly superior autonomous units
compared to the Legion.
Not one fatality has taken place
since their introduction.
That's not true. People have died!
Today, we have a real Handler
who serves as a Juggernaut
command and control officer.
This is Vladilena Milizé.
She wants to speak to you.
What I'm about to tell you
is the real history of the Republic.
Nine years ago, the Republic's regular army
was brought to the point of collapse
in just a little over two weeks
by the Legion's overwhelming firepower.
The Republic's government went on
to make two decisions.
The first was to withdraw of all its citizens
into 85 administrative districts.
The other was to pass the
Special Wartime Peace Preservation Act.
This law stripped citizenship and all rights
from anyone who did not have silver hair
and eyes like us Alba.
They would no longer be considered humans,
and instead would be kept
in carefully monitored internment camps
outside the 85 districts.
And due to that, as you're all aware,
the now supposedly empty area
became known as the 86th district,
and the people who live
there became known as Eighty-Six.
There they were forced to build
the fortress Gran Mur—
the wall isolating the 86th district—
and to pilot the Juggernauts.
There are humans inside the Juggernauts!
But because the ones inside,
the Eighty-Six, aren't "human,"
we say they're autonomous!
And even as we speak, they're out there,
surrounded by Legion and fighting!
The news you see every morning isn't true.
People are dying!
Dozens can die in a single battle.
But they're not human, right?
They're humanoid pigs that failed to evolve.
They're human!
I fight with them every day!
You say you fight with them.
But have you ever gone to the battlefield?
I have. Just once.
I went to the battlefield,
but I didn't fight.
The only ones who risk their lives
in battle are the Eighty-Six,
the people we stripped all rights from.
You can't do this, Major!
I told you not to say anything that sounds
like you've sided with them!
Sir, what does our nation's flag stand for?
What are you...
Freedom, equality, brotherhood,
justice, and nobility.
And those apply only to humans!
The Eighty-Six look human, but they aren't!
You mustn't misinform my students!
The Eighty-Six are teenage
boys and girls, just like us!
But they don't enjoy entertainment
and luxuries the way we do.
They can't laugh innocently
the way we do.
We can't leave them all alone!
We can't see them,
but if we listen carefully,
we can hear the voices
of these nameless soldiers!
Even apart, we look at the same stars!
And you told the new recruits that?
Yes.
This time you'll get punished, right?
Don't worry.
Uncle Jérôme will tell them
how firmly I believe in this.
You're surprisingly cunning about that.
You're being protected, huh?
It's not too late to change
the Republic's foolish mistake!
Right, right.
So, how was your meeting
with the famous Undertaker?
We're communicating regularly.
We synchronize with the Para-RAID nightly.
Nightly?
What do you talk about?
Lots of stuff.
Some of it not related
to work or the mission.
Even apart, our hearts are connected.
I told you not to get too attached.
A capable leader with solid combat skills,
who's a little reckless, but bold.
He's a very good soldier.
Undertaker isn't the scary man
they say he is.
That's just what you think, right?
Your heart rate's elevated.
After Action Report
This, too...
And this, and this...
Jeez...
Para-RAID, activate.
Synchronization target: Spearhead Processor.
Okay, one hit on King Bear,
two on Bunny Knight.
May 29th, Stellar Year 2148
Haruto gets seven points!
I missed two shots, huh?
I'm just not that good with handguns.
Fido set the can sideways! Kaie!
What do you think?
Kaie Taniya, initiating mission!
Point 208.
That's what that Handler woman said, right?
It would've been the ideal deployment point,
if we'd left at that moment.
Next, Kurena!
Fido, don't line them up! Throw them!
Yeah. It's such a teacher's-pet answer
that it makes me want to throw up,
but she's not just some spoiled rich kid.
Raiden, you're up!
Okay!
But how long can she keep up?
Hey, Kitty!
Here you go.
Thanks.
Anju!
I'll help you.
Thanks!
Yeah, sure thing.
I'll pass out Anju's cake!
Yay!
Is that a good book?
When I'm thinking about something else,
it stops me from focusing on it.
I see.
It's always a lot of stress for you, huh?
Shin, your turn!
At least stand up! You're no fun!
All units, may I have a word?
A new record. A full continuous week.
It's fine.
Handler One, good work today.
Yes, you too.
You all seemed to be having a lot of fun.
We were just killing time.
Don't worry about it.
I see.
By the way, Undertaker,
I need to scold you today.
What is it?
I went to read the patrol and combat
reports you'd filed
since your arrival in Spearhead,
and they were all the same.
Why do you care
what happens on the front lines?
You like to waste your time, huh?
Part of a Handler's job is analyzing
Legion tactics and formation tendencies.
I understand that you don't send them
because we don't read them.
That's our fault, so I'm not mad.
But from now on, do it properly.
I'll read them.
I'm not good at reading and writing.
Well, there were no schools in the camps.
I'm sorry!
It's not so much "not good at,"
but more "too lazy to."
Right, Undertaker?
Undertaker?
Very well.
Send me one for all your missions
up to this point as well.
Will footage from the gun camera do?
No. Write them.
If we can analyze them,
we can counter them.
You're an ace unit,
so your records are especially valuable.
We can lower attrition
across the whole battlefield,
including your unit. So help me, please.
So young.
No, I'm about the same age
as all of you.
How long has it been
since you joined the military?
We're all in our fourth year, I guess?
Undertaker's been here the longest.
It's his fifth year.
So Undertaker's almost done
with his term, huh?
Is there something you want to do
when you leave the army
and become a Republic citizen again?
Somewhere you want to go, or want to see?
I've never thought about it.
I see.
But you might want
to start thinking about it now.
You might come up with something.
I'm sure it'll be fun.
You may be right.
"I Don't Want to Die."